Richie Lombano

richylombano@gmail.com | St. Petersburg, US | resume.iosphere.tech

Summary

Experienced Site Reliability Engineer with a focus on GitOps and a demonstrated history of building secure, reliable platforms. Passionate about enabling product teams through SRE practices and DevOps culture, with a strong belief in 'shift left' principles.

Skills

- GitOps & Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Terraform, ArgoCD
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Azure
- CI/CD: Secure pipelines, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI
- Observability: Datadog, Opentelemetry, Tracing & APM
- Leadership & Agile: Mentoring, leading SRE teams, Agile methodologies

Work Experience

Solar Mosaic Oct 2022 - Present

Staff Site Reliability Engineer

As a Staff Site Reliability Engineer at Mosaic, I spearhead key initiatives to enhance our platform's stability and efficiency. I led the successful migration to EKS, cut our cloud costs by 50%, and significantly boosted service availability. I lead our CI/CD and infrastructure architecture and actively contribute to the health and security of our services. Collaborating with the application architecture committee, I help design and approve reference architectures. Currently, I'm leading the development of our internal developer platform, aiming to streamline self-service golden paths for our engineering teams.

- EKS Migration with Karpenter Autoscaling
- API Gateway modernization w/ NGINX & ingress-nginx
- Platform engineering self-service portal for engineers
 CI/CD for secure SDLC workflows

Jan 2021 — Oct 2022 **Panzura**

Senior Cloud Platform Engineer

Working to improve the DevOps culture at Panzura by integrating tooling and policies designed to help Product teams release faster while maintaining high security standards. Leveraging Infrastructure-as-Code, CI/CD pipelines, observability tooling, self-service, and an overall shift-left mentality wherever possible. Leading a team of three engineers.

Vology Nov 2016 — Apr 2020

Cloud Engineer

- Designed and migrated customer IT infrastructure to public cloud
- Conducted cloud readiness assessments and migration planning
- · Palo Alto and FortiGate firewalls in Azure
- Reference architectures for Azure offerings
- Colocation upgrades to Simplivity HCI and Nimble Storage
- Microsoft audit remediation

RobbinsKersten Direct Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Jr. Systems Engineer

Managed post-acquisition IT setup and built secure infrastructure and workflows.

- · Windows Server infrastructure design
- SSL VPN with 2FA & RDP Web remote access

Lincare Holdings, Inc.

Apr 2014 — Dec 2015

Systems Support

Managed deployment and support for thousands of workstations and servers, ensuring HIPAA compliance.

Jan 2011 — Apr 2014 **Elite Networks**

Subcontractor (Part Time)

Provided IT support and maintained infrastructure and uptime for hosted services.

Projects

Resume Pipeline

https://github.com/RLProteus/Resume

A simple pipeline to generate my resume in various formats using the popular project, JSON Resume. This allows me to keep my resume up to date with minimal effort and ensure it's consistant across all platforms.

For a more up-to-date list of projects, please visit my website at resume.iosphere.tech

Education

Pasco-Hernando Community College

Associate of Arts

Aug 2010 — Dec 2013

Awards & Recognitions

- Florida Bright Futures ScholarshipAll Florida Community College Academic Team Scholarship